<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamikaze chicken</title>
    <link>https://saahitya.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kamikaze chicken</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saahitya.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hampta Pass Journal Entries</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/hampta-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/hampta-journal/</guid>
      <description>11 July ⁃	Making everyone hurry in the morning to get to the airport ⁃	But my phone had no charge, iphone cable doesn&#39;t work with power bank ⁃	TIL - 2 rupee lounge ⁃	Is Turbulence just driving in clouds =&amp;gt; like going over potholes ⁃	Walk out of Delhi Airport - damn hot ⁃	Terrible terrible coffee ⁃	Bus ride - 500 kms - loud Dhaba with randos signing in Haryanvi  12 July ⁃	Raining and hair pin bendy roads all the way to Manali ⁃	Get ready fast, submit all docs ⁃	Goto start point of trek in sumo, at top ⁃	Crows seems to be there at the top of the mountains for some reason unlike pigeons in Manali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging in Drupal</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/drupal-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/drupal-logging/</guid>
      <description>Setting up logging today prevents the headache tommorow
Components  syslog - inbuilt drupal module to log drupal errors(no particular reason for choosing this module, can use any appropriate module that logs to file or write a module that implements hook_watchdog) logrotate - to archive the old logs to help classify by data and save space.  Steps  We enable syslog in the modules in drupal and save with the default config add a file in /etc/rsyslog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Design Guideline</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/solid-grasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/solid-grasp/</guid>
      <description>In college we were taught SOLID and GRASP principles which was more heuristics than principles1 that was supposed to make our code better. I honestly don&amp;#39;t know whether applying them helps as I never could remember it and I definitely wasn&amp;#39;t thinking about applying it when I was writing code. But one thing that did stay with me from college that was taught and repeated dozens of times by a great professor was the idea of interface and implementation, which was beautifully taught in C++ with the interface being written in the header file and the implementation being written in the library source file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Endurance the Right Way</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/endurance-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/endurance-notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes taken while listening to Building Endurance the Right Way
Aspects to Endurance - Cardio &amp;amp; Muscular  How to develop cardio  Steady state exercise - run at particular speed not too fast    Cause: Heart stretches when you increase heart rate upto a certain point which increases stroke volume(means a bigger heart)
  Running at increased heart rate (90% +), heart is twitching and not effective</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESG Stocks</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/esg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/esg/</guid>
      <description>I have a definitely-not-well-thought-out theory about ESG(Environmental, Social and Goverance) stocks. Hunch: ESG stocks will continue to generally always give better returns than the overall stock market.    In 10th grade I remember our English teacher asking whether it is moral for a person to own a luxury car since it is so polluting and one of my classmates made the point that people buy luxury cars as status symbol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightcrawler</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/running-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/running-at-night/</guid>
      <description>For the first time ever, I ran a 4k in the night at 11:30 PM around my apartment, that too after staying up for a software release. People talk about starting your day fresh after a run inconveniantly missing out the part about waking up early in the morning, and hustling after the run to get to work on time. In contrast when you run at night, you really don&amp;#39;t have anything to get back to except your bed and when you do get back you obviously will sleep like a log cause you are tired after running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Half Marathon 2019 Race Report</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/bm-race-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/bm-race-report/</guid>
      <description>Overall my memory of the race is very hazy and I remeber very specific parts of the race with not much long term context to it The beginning parts of the race involved a lot of shifting between lanes as some people were running slow and it was still relatively crowded approx for atleast 5-7 kms.
The course through cubbon park was generally very cool and the air there was very fresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>You-Know-Who Blog name inspired from this scene in Curb your Enthusiasm Kamakaze Pilot1
Personal brain dump. Get paid to read and write backend(mostly) code.
Resume
  Here&amp;rsquo;s some other &amp;ldquo;Kamakaze Chicken&amp;rdquo; material I found online
 Kamakaze Chicken Recipe Kamakaze Chicken 1 Kamakaze Chicken 2  &amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terribly plain photos</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/photos/</guid>
      <description>If you are going to put up some pictures on the internet you&amp;rsquo;ve got to atleast put up nice aesthetic color-graded shots or atleast have some person in it, unless you are me in which case you can put up pictures of random things, label it terribly and get away with it.
Don&#39;t be shy little frog  Trails are not always softer than the road to run on  One season later --- Ouch that must really hurt --- Lonely Bush in the middle of the trail --- Breakfast I --- Breakfast II --- Breakfast III --- Top Secret Location --- Kaccha Mango Bite </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
