<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review on saahityaedams</title>
    <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on saahityaedams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saahityaedams.github.io/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Tell Me I Can&#39;t Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/dont-tell-me-i-cant-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/dont-tell-me-i-cant-review/</guid>
      <description>The book &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Tell Me I Can&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo; is the memoir of an ambitious 14 year old who is homeschooled. It is singular in its genre for being heartfelt and authentic. Reading this book really did feel like a very mature child talking to me. The fact that is 73 pages and written in plain conversational English makes for a great one sitting read.
The book written in first person by Cole Summers (pseudonym) talks about his homeschooling journey which includes starting multiple businesses (I love that he derives inspiration and quotes Buffet and Munger throughout the book).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moneyball Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/moneyball-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/moneyball-review/</guid>
      <description>Rough Notes
Reading the book moneyball felt like a slog (maybe I would be better off watching the movie) and made me feel like the book was overhyped. This could be due to the fact that I knew zilch about baseball before reading the book, and had to do basic wikipedia research while reading the book.
The narrative while strong within a chapter didn&amp;rsquo;t flow through the whole book and the later part of the book felt boring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Presents Please Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/no-presents-please-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/no-presents-please-review/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;No Presents Please&amp;rsquo; was a fun, light and breezy first read of the year, consisting of 16 short stories set in Mumbai. Following the lives of working and middle-class characters (from the 1990s?), the stories capture people&amp;rsquo;s interactions against the backdrop of their daily work lives, reminded me of a less romantic and primitive version of the Modern Love TV show.
The characters resonated with me deeply, partly due to the nostalgic setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing Bridges(2013) Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/crossing-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/crossing-bridges/</guid>
      <description>Crossing Bridges(2013) is an unusual movie. Unlike a typical Bollywood movie, it does not have drama, nor is it like the recent Biopicy style movies that show the protagonist overcoming an obstacle, yet the movie was engrossing and my connection with the protagonist so strong that I did not pick up my phone more than twice while watching it.
– SPOILERS AHEAD –
The movie starts by showing a man called Tashi who has returned to his village in Arunachal Pradesh from Mumbai after being laid off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
