<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on saahityaedams</title>
    <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on saahityaedams</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://saahityaedams.github.io/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>28 Years Later Movie Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/28_years_later_move_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/28_years_later_move_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to see the movie 28 Years Later with no expectations &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;(I thought it could be a (trashy ?) zombie horror movie), but found this movie to be suprisingly quality film-making - great story, great acting, good cinematography &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Roughly, the story is about the protagonist teenager Spikey who is part of a survivor village holed up in an island off mainland (Britain) after a virus turns pretty-much-everyone-else into zombies and his adventures visiting the mainland and his encounters with the zombies. I really liked the movie and I think it ranks highly amongst other greats in the genre like Apocalypto and Train to Busan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scaling Era Book Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/gcpp_artifacts/the_scaling_era_book_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/gcpp_artifacts/the_scaling_era_book_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dwarkesh&amp;rsquo;s book - &amp;ldquo;The Scaling Era&amp;rdquo; (25th March 2025, Stripe Press) is a delightful oddity. It&amp;rsquo;s uniquely formatted - mostly as snippets of his podcast episodes related to AI categorized across crucial aspects of LLMs like Safety and Scaling. The book is a superb highlight reel of Dwarkesh&amp;rsquo;s podcast, reflecting the excellent quality of his show (superb guest quality, discourse quality, intellectual topics, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book excels at discussing the not-strictly technical &amp;amp; under-discussed aspects of LLMs like inference scaling, cluster sizes, and impacts of AGI. Dwarkesh has meticulously edited/curated the interviews and referenced important material discussed in his podcasts (references and glossary made up about 50% of the book on my Kindle). The format also excels in bringing readers perspectives from diverse experts in a relaxed conversation format - both AI doomers (like Yudkowsky) and folks with more nuanced opinions (like Gwern).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Tell Me I Can&#39;t Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/dont-tell-me-i-cant-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/dont-tell-me-i-cant-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The book &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Tell Me I Can&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo; is the memoir of an ambitious 14 year old who is homeschooled. It is singular in its genre for being heartfelt and authentic. Reading this book really did feel like a very mature child talking to me. The fact that is 73 pages and written in plain conversational English makes for a great one sitting read.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book written in first person by Cole Summers (pseudonym) talks about his homeschooling journey which includes starting multiple businesses (I love that he derives inspiration and quotes Buffet and Munger throughout the book). From his first business at 7, breeding and selling rabbits, to then purchasing a 350 acre ranch (for rearing meat goats) at 9 and buying/renovating a house shortly after that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moneyball Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/moneyball-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/moneyball-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rough Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reading the book moneyball felt like a slog (maybe I would be better off watching the movie) and made me feel like the book was overhyped. This could be due to the fact that I knew zilch about baseball before reading the book, and had to do basic wikipedia research while reading the book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The narrative while strong within a chapter didn&amp;rsquo;t flow through the whole book and the later part of the book felt boring. In contrast, a narrative of this genre that I loved was &amp;ldquo;Soul of a new machine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Presents Please Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/no-presents-please-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/no-presents-please-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;No Presents Please&amp;rsquo; was a fun, light and breezy first read of the year, consisting of 16 short stories set in Mumbai. Following the lives of working and middle-class characters (from the 1990s?), the stories capture people&amp;rsquo;s interactions against the backdrop of their daily work lives, reminded me of a less romantic and primitive version of the Modern Love TV show.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The characters resonated with me deeply, partly due to the nostalgic setting. These are honest people making just enough to get by, living simpler lives while facing universal human challenges. Despite their modest circumstances, their stories touch on fundamental aspects of the human condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossing Bridges(2013) Review</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/ancient/crossing-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/ancient/crossing-bridges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crossing Bridges(2013) is an unusual movie. Unlike a typical Bollywood movie, it does not have drama, nor is it like the recent Biopicy style movies that show the protagonist overcoming an obstacle, yet the movie was engrossing and my connection with the protagonist so strong that I did not pick up my phone more than twice while watching it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;– SPOILERS AHEAD –&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie starts by showing a man called Tashi who has returned to his village in Arunachal Pradesh from Mumbai after being laid off. Tashi is shown as this guy who has come back to his village after a very long time working in the city as a YASP(yours truly) and hence doesn’t seem to fit in his village. Not that there is a lack of conflict in the movie, but the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s main conflict is so sublime and internal(just like most normal people): his parents want him to settle down in the village to take over the farm, he wants to get a job back in the city and move back as he is bored in the village. There are other non-crucial points in the storyline, him buying a TV as he is bored(Dad is against the idea, but is glued to it after he gets it), his friendly relationship with a fellow replacement teacher Anila&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, etc. Finally, Tashi decides to stay back in the village as a teacher even after getting a job in the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
