<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading on saahityaedams</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on saahityaedams</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Re: 2025 -&gt; 2026 Reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/drafts/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/drafts/reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;2025-retro&#34;&gt;2025 Retro&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first half of 2025 went great in terms of my reading. I started off the year strong with some fun reads and the momentum just kept me going for a while. I liked the fact that in hindsight my book choices were so weird, random and have no clear rhyme and rhythm. Some of the weird and wonderful books I liked were&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No Presents Please (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/no-presents-please-review/&#34;&gt;book review&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Tell Me I Can&amp;rsquo;t (About an enterprising home schooled kid from rural Utah who builds a ranch and more)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Service of the Republic (Incredibly good public policy book)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Scaling Era (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/gcpp_artifacts/the_scaling_era_book_review/&#34;&gt;book review&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Inner Game of Tennis (It&amp;rsquo;s not about tennis)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now coming to things that went bad for me this year. Understandly, I struggled to make time for reading in the last quarter since I was balancing (or struggling to balance more appropriately) work and a hectic semester of study (I really should have planned this better). Another pattern I noticed was I saw myself slipping into spending more time reading light-weight substack articles and tweets over long-form substantive books (or articles) I wished to read. I really started off the year, hoping to write more book reviews &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen too. My general observation has been, I enjoy writing book reviews and this feeds into a this feedback loop of getting me to read more books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
