<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System-Design on saahityaedams</title>
    <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/tags/system-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System-Design on saahityaedams</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://saahityaedams.github.io/tags/system-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Design Guideline</title>
      <link>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/ancient/solid-grasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saahityaedams.github.io/posts/ancient/solid-grasp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In college we were taught SOLID and GRASP principles which was more heuristics than principles&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-reference&#34;&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;footnote-reference-1&#34; href=&#34;#footnote-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that was supposed to make our code better. I honestly don&amp;#39;t know whether applying them helps as I never could remember it and I definitely wasn&amp;#39;t thinking about applying it when I was writing code. But one thing that did stay with me from college that was taught and repeated dozens of times by a great professor was the idea of &lt;strong&gt;interface and implementation&lt;/strong&gt;, which was beautifully taught in C++ with the interface being written in the header file and the implementation being written in the library source file. His point being &lt;strong&gt;interfaces&lt;/strong&gt; are static and hard to change and must be designed well and carefully, in contast with &lt;strong&gt;implementation&lt;/strong&gt;  being abstracted away from user and hence easy to change. A video he had asked us to look at that I recently rewatched after a year of being paid to write software makes a lot more sense now. The video expands on the above point + metions some other very usefull guidelines and is a must watch.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
