<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kamikaze chicken</title>
    <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kamikaze chicken</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saahitya.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Endurance the Right Way</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/endurance-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/endurance-notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes taken while listening to Building Endurance the Right Way
Aspects to Endurance - Cardio &amp;amp; Muscular  How to develop cardio  Steady state exercise - run at particular speed not too fast    Cause: Heart stretches when you increase heart rate upto a certain point which increases stroke volume(means a bigger heart)
  Running at increased heart rate (90% +), heart is twitching and not effective</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESG Stocks</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/esg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/esg/</guid>
      <description>I have a definitely-not-well-thought-out theory about ESG(Environmental, Social and Goverance) stocks. Hunch: ESG stocks will continue to generally always give better returns than the overall stock market.    In 10th grade I remember our English teacher asking whether it is moral for a person to own a luxury car since it is so polluting and one of my classmates made the point that people buy luxury cars as status symbol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running in the night for the first time</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/running-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/running-at-night/</guid>
      <description>For the first time ever, I ran a 4k in the night at 11:30 PM around my apartment, that too after staying up for a software release. People talk about starting your day fresh after a run inconveniantly missing out the part about waking up early in the morning, and hustling after the run to get to work on time. In contrast when you run at night, you really don&amp;#39;t have anything to get back to except your bed and when you do get back you obviously will sleep like a log cause you are tired after running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Half Marathon 2019 Race Report</title>
      <link>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/bm-race-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saahitya.github.io/posts/bm-race-report/</guid>
      <description>Overall my memory of the race is very hazy and I remeber very specific parts of the race with not much long term context to it The beginning parts of the race involved a lot of shifting between lanes as some people were running slow and it was still relatively crowded approx for atleast 5-7 kms.
The course through cubbon park was generally very cool and the air there was very fresh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
